<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Blocktag - Provably Authentic]]></title><description><![CDATA[The last mile in authenticity.]]></description><link>https://www.blocktag.com/website</link><image><url>https://www.blocktag.com/website/icons/icon-512x512.png</url><title>Blocktag - Provably Authentic</title><link>https://www.blocktag.com/website</link></image><generator>Blocktag - Provably Authentic</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 08:34:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.blocktag.com/website/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright><![CDATA[© 2020 Blocktag Inc. All rights reserved.]]></copyright><item><title><![CDATA[Deepfake For Good]]></title><description><![CDATA[Deepfake is an AI technology that digitally alters a person’s face so that they appear to be someone else. It is often used with bad…]]></description><link>https://www.blocktag.com/website/blog/deepfake-for-good/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.blocktag.com/website/blog/deepfake-for-good/</guid><category><![CDATA[blocktag]]></category><category><![CDATA[deepfake]]></category><category><![CDATA[authentication]]></category><category><![CDATA[fingerprint]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Deepfake is an AI technology that digitally alters a person’s face so that they appear to be someone else. It is often used with bad intentions. We turned the tables and found a use with good intentions. Blocktag uses deepfake to digitally alter an original tag so that you can anticipate how counterfeit tags look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blocktag’s deepfake technology learns the physics of printing to predict how photocopied tags printed on different printer models will look like. Below is an image rendering of deepfake reprints and photocopies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/deepfake-for-good1.png&quot; alt=&quot;DeepfakeTagSample1&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Deepfake reprints and photocopies derived from an original tag. Black pixels on red/green/blue colored background represents noisy areas that are masked out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, print physics differs on different paper types. Deepfake tags can be created more accurately if you know what material or paper is the tag printed on. The material or paper type is also useful to check print quality for users that print tags on home printers. Blocktag can infer paper type by seeing a tag’s surface texture with AI computer vision. An AI model is trained on images of tags printed on known paper types (Normal, cardboard, glossy, photo quality etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blocktag can also use AI to customize how deepfake tags look like on different phone cameras. Because cameras with different resolutions perceive the printed original tag at different sharpness. Sharper pixels can be misinterpreted as extra chaotic print artifacts from a photocopied tag. Blocktag AI corrects the camera focus to ensure a fair comparison between original and deepfake tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/deepfake-for-good2.png&quot; alt=&quot;DeepfakeTagSample2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Deepfake reprints derived from the same original tag taken with a higher resolution camera.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blocktag uses deepfakes to improve authentication accuracy. As we collect more training data from user authentications to train our deep learning model, there are more deepfake datapoints to tighten the minimum similarity threshold to pass authentication. You can visualize this in the 3D graph below. The x/y/z axis represents the target tag’s red/green/blue colored pattern similarity with it’s original fingerprint. The boxed space bounded by the 3 colored planes represent successful authentication. Each colored datapoint represents a tag instance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Deepfake empowers a brand’s users as anti-counterfeiting&apos;s first line of defense. Before counterfeiters try to fake it till they make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChunMing Chin&lt;br&gt;
Cofounder, Director of Engineering&lt;br&gt;
Blocktag Inc&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Long Live Violin]]></title><description><![CDATA[What is the origin of an instrument’s life?
From the growth of the Maple tree wood?
From the violin maker crafting its form?
From the…]]></description><link>https://www.blocktag.com/website/blog/long-live-violin-en/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.blocktag.com/website/blog/long-live-violin-en/</guid><category><![CDATA[blocktag]]></category><category><![CDATA[violin]]></category><category><![CDATA[digitaltwin]]></category><category><![CDATA[3D]]></category><category><![CDATA[AR]]></category><category><![CDATA[fingerprint]]></category><category><![CDATA[announcements]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;What is the origin of an instrument’s life?&lt;br&gt;
From the growth of the Maple tree wood?&lt;br&gt;
From the violin maker crafting its form?&lt;br&gt;
From the musician performing its voice?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The muscian&apos;s stories are recorded through the bow&apos;s back and forth movement across the strings of Time. The sounds of String vibration and Newtonian motion are carved into it&apos;s wood. The violin’s inner Space records all forms of vibrations, physical and emotional, as well as the stories behind them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/ViolinInside.png&quot; alt=&quot;Violin Inside&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Violin Inner Space&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People believe they are the lead soloist in their life’s symphony. But in the universe’s vast symphony, I am empty silence. The violin lives longer than me. It should remember its own stories as the lead performer. I am just a partner playing a supporting role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 16th century, Cremona Italy was the world capital of handcrafted violins. Each violin has its own printed “Certificato Di Authentica”. The violin’s unique fingerprint identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century, Blocktag is the printed tag technology for violin authentication. Each tag has its own unclonable fingerprint. When a violin is tagged, you can scan the tag with your phone camera and see the violin’s past life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time goes by, the violin’s life story can be recorded. For example, a partner musician’s performance recording at a concert hall. Generations of performers all the way back to the violin maker can be remembered this way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.blocktag.com/CNPFjZEG&quot;&gt;https://app.blocktag.com/CNPFjZEG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
This is the webpage linked to the tag inside my violin. The digital violin is the a 3D scan of the real violin, its digital twin. Blocktag is the eternal memory body of the violin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maker crafts it&apos;s form. The musician gives it life. Witness the evolution of each human generation.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Violin Digital Twin]]></title><description><![CDATA[A violinist has partnered with Blocktag to auction an authenticated, 3D scan model of her phyiscal violin on OpenSea https://opensea.io…]]></description><link>https://www.blocktag.com/website/blog/violin-digital-twin/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.blocktag.com/website/blog/violin-digital-twin/</guid><category><![CDATA[blocktag]]></category><category><![CDATA[violin]]></category><category><![CDATA[digitaltwin]]></category><category><![CDATA[3D]]></category><category><![CDATA[AR]]></category><category><![CDATA[fingerprint]]></category><category><![CDATA[announcements]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A violinist has partnered with Blocktag to auction an authenticated, 3D scan model of her phyiscal violin on OpenSea &lt;a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensea.io/collection/blocktag-violin-nft&quot;&gt;https://opensea.io/collection/blocktag-violin-nft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. You might be thinking: &quot;Is there value in buying a digital twin instead of the physical violin?&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/OpenSea1.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenSeaPage1&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/OpenSea2.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenSeaPage2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blocktag violin NFT collection on OpenSea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, experts authenticate violins by checking visual characteristics like the violin&apos;s varnish, wood grain pattern etc. Blocktag wants to resonate with this tradition by using the digital twin as the physical violin&apos;s 3D fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/AuthenticationCertificateHalf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Certificato Di Authentica&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Violin maker describing violin&apos;s visual characteristics on it&apos;s certificate of authenticity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Violin Authentication Evolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For basic authentication, the original violin&apos;s tag has a unique chaotic print signature that is recorded by the Blocktag camera app as a fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For advanced authentication, the original violin&apos;s visual properties near the tag e.g. Wood grain pattern, texture, shape etc. is recorded by the Blocktag camera app as a fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;373&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/tag.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Tag Surroundings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Basic authentiction with tag&apos;s chaotic fingerprint signature in orange box. &lt;br&gt; Advanced authentication with tag&apos;s surrounding features fingerprint in purple box&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For expert authentication, the entire original violin outside and inside can be 3D scanned as a digital twin fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/ViolinOutside.png&quot; alt=&quot;Violin Outside&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expert authentication with 3D digital twin fingerprint from the oustide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/ViolinInside.png&quot; alt=&quot;Violin Inside&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expert authentication with 3D digital twin fingerprint scan from the inside&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Augmented Reality Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;
To authenticate if a physical violin matches with its expected 3D digital twin fingerprint, Blocktag guides users to navigate their camera around the violin with Augmentated Reality (AR).
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/DigitalTwinAuthenticationAR.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Digital Twin Authentication AR&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source physical violin with 3D scanned digital twin AR on top. Users must navigate their phone camera to 3D blue plane to authenticate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tranform Piracy To Promotion&lt;/h2&gt;
The digital twin&apos;s varnish looks different from the physical violin as it is encrypted by Blocktag to prevent public access to the actual fingerprint. Only the owner can access the fingerprint by verifying they own the digital twin&apos;s Non Fungible Token (NFT) in their digital wallet. This security design transforms the threat of digital twin piracy into an opportunity. Pirates are welcome to freely copy the public digital twin to promote vintage violin art!
&lt;h2&gt;The Purest Representation&lt;/h2&gt;
The digital twin is the purest visual representation of the original violin. As &quot;The Red Violin&quot; movie shows, it is unavoidable that an antique violin is damaged over time. Once damaged, restoration with new parts does not look like the original violin. To preserve archives of the original violin, the tagged physical violin is 3D scanned.
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3feDUcDRNAg&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChunMing Chin&lt;br&gt;
Cofounder, Director of Engineering&lt;br&gt;
Blocktag Inc&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Red Violin: Timeless Memory]]></title><description><![CDATA[Blocktag wants to amplify this timeless appreciation for art. The violin's stories will be remembered through Blocktag's authentication tag…]]></description><link>https://www.blocktag.com/website/blog/the-red-violin-timeless-memory/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.blocktag.com/website/blog/the-red-violin-timeless-memory/</guid><category><![CDATA[blocktag]]></category><category><![CDATA[violin]]></category><category><![CDATA[announcements]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;The Red Violin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you wondered why someone would spend millions on antique art? A movie The Red Violin has an answer. The movie&apos;s main character is a red violin, filmed from the violin’s point of view. From its birth in Cremona Italy during the 1700s. To its ownership by an English lord in Britain during the 1800s Victorian royal era. Then, its near destruction in Shanghai during the 1900s Cultural Revolution. And eventually, its auction for millions in modern day Montreal. The Red Violin is based on the real life violin of 1720 called the Red Mendelssohn, which sold for $1.7million in 1990&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TQPzlH1QV-w&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Timeless Art Appreciation&lt;/h2&gt;
As an art appreciation, the violin lets you hear and touch memories of the past. The violin plays a string of past life memories shared with its human owners.
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/ViolinLook.png&quot; alt=&quot;ViolinLook&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Violinists often peer into the f-hole to see what is written in the violin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blocktag wants to amplify this timeless appreciation for art. The violin&apos;s stories will be remembered through Blocktag&apos;s authentication tag. Scan the Blocktagged violin with your phone camera and you can watch a real life version of &quot;The Red Violin&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/samples/BlocktagViolin3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blocktag app scan violin&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A new way to peer into the f-hole&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shared memory could be a digitized certificate of authenticity issued by the original violin maker as well as stories of the owner, appraiser, restorer and other professionals that have taken care of the violin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/AuthenticationCertificate.png&quot; alt=&quot;Certificato Di Authentica&quot;&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or a performance recording by a musician with the violin. Like this 2020AD pandemic era shared memory with a masked performer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/674119192?h=e17aa6274c&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Blocktag Timeless Art Appreciation&lt;/h2&gt;
Blocktag is partnering with a violinist to let people appreciate this timeless form of art. Her violin is crafted by a violin maker (Luthier) and featured by the Associazione Liutaria Italiana in Cremona Italy, the world capital for handcrafted violins. If you buy the 3D scanned &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blocktag.com/blog/violin-digital-twin/&quot;&gt;Digital Twin&lt;/a&gt; of this physical tagged violin on the OpenSea marketplace, you can access all of the violin&apos;s recorded memories: &lt;a&gt;https://opensea.io/collection/blocktag-violin-nft&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/OpenSea1.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenSeaPage1&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/OpenSea2.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenSeaPage2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Blocktag violin NFT collection on OpenSea&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PS: Safeguard Memory With Non Fungible Token (NFT) &lt;/h2&gt;
To safeguard the violin&apos;s recorded digital memory from tampering, a violin&apos;s story recorded through Blocktag is unchangeable (non fungible). When this unchangeable unit (token) of data is stored on a digital ledger, it is known as a Non Fungible Token (NFT). Combining the tagged physical violin and its digital data forms a physical NFT. Read more at &lt;a&gt;https://www.blocktag.com/blog/violin-physical-nft/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChunMing Chin&lt;br&gt;
Cofounder, Director of Engineering&lt;br&gt;
Blocktag Inc&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>